Diego Favero

Full Stack WebDeveloper (resume)

Portifolio: https://orisha1.gitlab.io/my_site/

Samples: https://github.com/orisha/SampleCodesPHPJavaScriptGoLang

GitHub: https://github.com/orisha

StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/688689/diego-favero

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/faverodiego/

Brazilian 16th, May, 1981

 ${\it diego.g. favero@gmail.com}$

+55 75 998123412

Bachelor's degree in Information Systems.

@ São Paulo State University (UNESP)

Since 2003

Portuguese : Mother Tongue

English: Advanced Spanish: Intermediary Italian, French: Basic

Most Used		
BackEnd	PHP (Symfony Laravel) Golang	
FrontEnd	TypeScript JavaScript React jQuery Vue	
Agile	Jira Trello RunRun.it	
DevOps	Linux Docker circleCl sonarCloud AWS GitLab	
DataBase	MySql MongoDB Postgres	
Mobile	Kotlin	
Techniques	Microservice EDD API OOP Ajax TDD BDD	
Want to Learn	Machine Learning Data Science DevOps Automation DevSecOps	

Formal Work Experience	
Alooba	FullStack Software Engineer. My daily activities are basically to kill bugs on legacy app and develop new features on the v2 app. Besides the coding, I also have to : Test and/or Code review other co-workers tasks.
NetSar	Senior PHP Programmer. I was leading a small team (me plus 2 programmers, occasionally a designer) responsible for re-write the old scripts into a new Symfony based platform. Eventually, I did write codes for new features. Most of the system was based on SOAP/REST.

I am multitasking with vast tech knowledge: I can fit in many positions in the IT team.

My interests go through UI/UX, AR, Machine Learning, Data Science and other. Keep scrolling to see my full Curriculum.

Diego Favero Full Stack WebDeveloper (full CV)

Online Resume and Code Samples: http://18.216.194.20/diegofavero.dev/

GitHub: https://github.com/orisha

StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/688689/diego-favero

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/faverodiego/

Brazilian, Born at: 16th, May, 1981 E-mail: diego.g.favero@gmail.com Phone: +55 75 998123412

Common Used Tools

#PHP #MYSQL #GOLANG

#REACT #LINUX #JAVASCRIPT

#SYMFONY #TYPESCRIPT #DOCKER

About me:

I have been using **PHP** and its 'sidekicks' for web development since **1999** when I started to be an intern in the university's computer's lab.

Today I am able to work in any stage from a system development:

Since analyzing system requirements, going through server setup, database design and administration, team managing, coding (Structure, **Backend** and Frontend), test and deployment!

Currently, I have based my personal projects on **microservice** architecture. Using **Golang** as BackEnd . Professionally I use PHP and TypeScript.

I am really up to start to learn new technologies.

Today, I consider myself a better fit as a **backend developer** than frontend.

I Have a good knowledge about Photography, Video Editing and Audio Production, able to use many softwares such as Adobe suite, Logic Pro, Ableton Live and many others.

I have been DJing since 2007.

As a hobby I like outdoor sports such as rock climbing, trekking and mountain biking, and sometimes, I make awesome woodwork! (Most of my house's furniture is made by me).

Technical Skills

Level 8 (I would be able to perform a workshop of these right now)

PHP OOP Mysql

Level 7 (I can work very well using these, with some kind of expertise)

Javascript Jquery Symfony PHPStorm (IDE) OSX Linux

Level 6 (I Can do it! Maybe I'll use google to check any syntax or a forgotten detail)

GoLang API **TypeScript** Mysql Server Git **AWS** SOAP/REST SEO DBA TDD Kotlin Docker React Nginx BDD SASS/LESS CSS3 HTML5

Level 5 (I can do it! I have already used it! Just give a few days on google)

XML Vue .js Design Patterns Node.js Angular SSL / HTTPS

Level 4 (tools I already used, but not that much, so I am able to use it)

ExtJS Kendo UI Codelgniter

Level 3 (I know what is and how to apply, but never worked using those before)

Ruby NoSql WordPress Bootstrap Pearl Kubernetes

Level 2 (Languages I learned in college, but never used professionally)

C, C++ Java Pascal Cobol Lua Delphi Assemble Fortran ASP

Education:

Title: Bachelor

Course: Information Systems Bachelor's Degree at **UNESP** (Sao Paulo State University) from March 1999 until December 2003

The Course, basically, is a shortened form of Science Computers **plus** company management course. In short words: **It teaches how to apply computers based systems for companies**.

- * Original title in portuguese : Bacharelado em Sistemas de Informação.
- ** The <u>Information Systems Bachelor</u> at UNESP is the first course of its kind in Brazil. And since them it has been always ranked as #1 in Brazil.
- ***The Sao Paulo State University is in the top 4 Brazilian Ranking and it is in the top 400 world wide.

Languages Skills

Portuguese (pt-BR): native speaker.

English: Advanced

I (really) learned English when was **living** in Amsterdam (2008-2009), today I could say that I am aware of my strong Brazilian accent, also a few mess when need to use 'in', 'on', 'at', etc, although, I think I can **express** myself clearly enough to hold any kind of conversation, written or **spoken**.

Spanish: Intermediary

Due to its **similarity** to portuguese, I can understand spanish very well when spoken and fully when read . But I can not speak as good as I speak English

French/Italian: Self Learning

Like Spanish, these other **latin** languages are kind of easy to understand, but I still don't get much of it when spoken. I just need a bit more practice.

Work Experience

__<u>Alooba</u> FullStack Software Engineer Jul 2020 — Feb 2021 Australian Based Company - Home Office.

It is a startup company from Australia which recently got a substantial investment. It provides **solutions** for hiring processes focused on Data Sciences roles.

My daily tasks:

- Quickly fix bugs (Mostly from monolithic "old app").
 - Stack: PHP, Postgres, Jquery, Javascript, React (class), Cron Jobs.
- _ Migration : The "Old App" has been migrated to a microservice architecture.
- Add new features. As the migration evolves, new features have been added to the services.
- Stack: Laravel (Lumen), Microservices, Docker, Postgres, Event Driven, Test (phpUnit & Jest), React (functional), TypeScript.
- Code Review & Testing on tasks done by other developers .
- _ Monitoring Productions Errors (OpsGenies).

Self Employed : One Man Army - Aug 2014 - Jun 2020

AnyWhere - Digital Nomade.

The idea was to have a management system generic enough to attend any demand and specific enough to actually solve the demand.

Using the concepts of product, service and sectors, the system is able to calculate all the costs considering all the steps on a production lifecycle.

With a few modifications (mostly about labels), the very same system was used to manage.

- _ Dried fruit production. From soil preparation until the final product.
- _ Warehouse from a big electronic music festival.
- _ Hostel. Managed the available and allotted beds and reservations.
- _ Bar. Could manage the daily accounts and liquor stock.

The last version got lots of new features in order to manage music festivals.

- _ Ticket generation and online selling.
- _ Check in on site.
- _ NFC cards, credits, top up, spending (for internal consumption of food and beverages)
- _ Real-time accounting

I had a very nice MVP, two solid clients, then, the covid iced this project.

My role here was basically everything: Project, design, architecture, frontend, backend, devops, dba, marketing, selling, legal concerns, new features, etc

NetSar Senior PHP Programmer nov 2012 — Jul 2014 Brazilian Based Company - Home Office

It is a medium software company in Brazil providing **solutions** for travel shop's. It was a home based job. I was **leading** a small team (me plus 2 programmers, occasionally a designer) responsible for re-write the old scripts into a new **Symfony** based platform . Eventually, I did write codes for new features . Most of the system was based on **SOAP/REST** servers!

Reason for getting off: In may 2014 I had a motorcycle crash, which costs me three broken ribs, a pierced lung, a week in the hospital and almost my life. After that I decided to give myself some time so I asked to get off for travel.

_ <u>Advosoft</u> PHP Developer Jun 2012 — Oct 2012 USA Based company. - Home Office

It was a home based job. I was simply coding new **features** according to the projects previously sent through some collab tool .

Reason for getting off: They let me go without further explanation.

<u>Ecentry</u> Jr PHP Developer - Jan 2010 — Dec 2011 Brazil Based Company - Office Based Job

I Was working on a Fidelity Program System owned by **Lufthansa** Flight Company. This system is responsible for managing the Fidelity Points Program for the ones who sell Lufthansa tickets. It was a huge system within almost **2M** users, translated into more than 80 **languages**.

I had two main functions:

- 1 **Maintenance**: Had to quickly fix any reported bug.
- 2 New Interface and Database **Optimization**: While no bugs were reported, I had a mission to check and optimize the **SQL's** query and system performance. To do so, I was migrating all queries to be executed by **Python** Scripts.

The new interface was developed using **ExtJS** Framework.

Reason to get off: I was sick of having to spend two hours every day into the Brazilian mad traffic. After being denied to work home based, I asked to quit!

My Goals

_ MultiTask and vast tech knowledge: I can fit in many positions in the IT department.
_ Can travel or move in anytime .
_ Dare me on new challenges !
_ I think 'out the box' and love to learn.
_ I can inject new market vision ('cause I live the Brazilian reality, would be a nice info and
experiences exchange about this huge and growing marketing we have around here).

Interests

Augmented Reality UI / UX New Technologies

Qubits Data Security Networks

Big Data Machine Learning IA

Interests beyond IT

A few things I like to do and **learn** about in my spare time:

_ Photo / Video / Audio Production and Edition
_ Sports -> Climbing, Mountain bike, Surf, SlackLine and Trekking.
_ Healthier life and food .
_ Travel
_ Quantum physics.
_ Yoga and Capoeira .
_ Politics and Economy .
_ Dogs .
_ Simple Life .
Carpenter and Architecture .

Why hire me?

Because I have a full **domain** about how to attend to the job needs (if hooded by my **skills**, otherwise, I am fully open to learn it) with a few pluses acquired by life experience. And, I have a passion for working with **technologies**!

Want to see more?

Please, ask for a code sample and I will be glad to send a few files with pieces of code I've written